<CommonElement name="SIF_Metadata" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Intro>
    <p>
      Metadata is commonly referred to as data about data and includes information such as author, grade level, or keywords relating to a learning object, as examples.
      Metadata can be used to structure and contain any of this kind of information in a consistent manner.
      In the context of SIF, <code>SIF_Metadata</code> provides a consistent structure to appropriate SIF objects for the purpose of cataloging and object discovery,
      as well as other metadata functions and purposes.  One recurring use case within the SIF data model is the requirement for some form of temporal constraints and tagging
      on objects (see <a href="#TimeElement">
        <code>TimeElement</code>
      </a>).  Other metadata elements are based on needs brought to the Data Model Task Force.
    </p>

    <p>
      <strong>IMPORTANT NOTE ON PERSISTENCE</strong>
    </p>

    <p>
      This data is not designed to be permanent.
      It is designed to frame an object instance and could dissolve as soon as it leaves the SIF framework for the application space.
      A data warehouse could be used to store metadata for later tracking.
    </p>


    <p>
      <strong>IMPORTANT NOTE ON USAGE</strong>
    </p>
    <p>
      Any usage of metadata is optional unless made a requirement
      within individual SIF objects, or if a SIF or local profile or zone installation mandates it.  SIF_Metadata allows for the usage of metadata in agents and applications that choose to support it.
    </p>
    <p>This element is designed to operate much like SIF_ExtendedElements.  It is an approved common element that is part of any data object.</p>
  </Intro>
  <Item>
    <Element>SIF_Metadata</Element>
    <Description>
      <p>A commonly defined container for metadata elements defined within SIF.</p>
    </Description>
  </Item>
  
  <xi:include parse="text" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="Custom/SIF_Metadata-Elements-Custom.xml"/>
  <xi:include parse="text" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="Custom/SIF_Metadata-Example-Custom.xml"/>

</CommonElement>

