<SIFSpecification xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xhtml="https://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml/" xmlns="http://sifassociation.org/SpecGen">				  

	<BuildComment>
		SIF Implementation Specification (Australia) 3.6.3


		(November 40, 2024)
		
		Infrastructure Version: v3
		
		These schema files are licensed under the Apache 2.0 License. See https://home.a4l.org/legal/ 
	</BuildComment>
	
	<!--Title Page-->
	<TitlePage>
		<h1>
			Systems Interoperability Framework™<br />
			SIF Implementation Specification (Australia) 3.6.3


		</h1>
		<h2>
			November 40, 2024
		</h2>
		<br />
		<br />
		<br />
		<p>
			<img src="images/zone.jpg" alt="" />
		</p>
		<br />
		<br />
		<dl>
			<dt>This version:</dt>
			<dd>
				<a href="http://specification.sifassociation.org/Implementation/AU/3.6.3/1/index.html">http://specification.sifassociation.org/Implementation/AU/3.6.3/1/index.html</a>
			</dd>
			<dt>Previous version:</dt>
			<dd>
				<a href="http://specification.sifassociation.org/Implementation/AU/3.6.2/">http://specification.sifassociation.org/Implementation/AU/3.6.2/</a>
			</dd>
			<dt>Latest version:</dt>
			<dd>
				<a href="http://specification.sifassociation.org/Implementation/AU/">http://specification.sifassociation.org/Implementation/AU/</a>
			</dd>
			<dt>API Documentation</dt>
			<dd>
			<a href="ServiceDocs/index.html">Data Model Services</a>
			</dd>
			<dt>XML Schemas</dt>
			<dd>
				<a href="XSD/SIF_MessageNoIncludes/SIF_Message.xsd">SIF_Message (single file, non-annotated)</a>
				<a href="XSD/SIF_MessageNoIncludes.zip">(ZIP archive)</a>
			</dd>
			<dd>
				<a href="XSD/SIF_MessageNoIncludesAnnotated/SIF_Message.xsd">SIF_Message (single file, annotated)</a>
				<a href="XSD/SIF_MessageNoIncludesAnnotated.zip">(ZIP archive)</a>
			</dd>
			<dd>
				<a href="XSD/SIF_Message/SIF_Message.xsd">SIF_Message (includes, non-annotated)</a>
				<a href="XSD/SIF_Message.zip">(ZIP archive)</a>
			</dd>
			<dd>
				<a href="XSD/SIF_MessageAnnotated/SIF_Message.xsd">SIF_Message (includes, annotated)</a>
				<a href="XSD/SIF_MessageAnnotated.zip">(ZIP archive)</a>
			</dd>
			<dd>
				<a href="XSD/DataModelNoIncludes/SIF_Message.xsd">DataModel (single file, non-annotated)</a>
				<a href="XSD/DataModelNoIncludes.zip">(ZIP archive)</a>
			</dd>
			<dd>
				<a href="XSD/DataModelNoIncludesAnnotated/SIF_Message.xsd">DataModel (single file, annotated)</a>
				<a href="XSD/DataModelNoIncludesAnnotated.zip">(ZIP archive)</a>
			</dd>
			<dd>
				<a href="XSD/DataModel/SIF_Message.xsd">DataModel (includes, non-annotated)</a>
				<a href="XSD/DataModel.zip">(ZIP archive)</a>
			</dd>
			<dd>
				<a href="XSD/DataModelAnnotated/SIF_Message.xsd">DataModel (includes, annotated)</a>
				<a href="XSD/DataModelAnnotated.zip">(ZIP archive)</a>
			</dd>
			<dd style="font-size: smaller">
				<br />
				<em>Note:</em>
				<em>SIF_Message</em> schemas define every data object element as optional per SIF's Publish/Subscribe and SIF Request/Response Models; 
				<em>DataModel</em> schemas maintain the cardinality of all data object elements.
			</dd>
		    <dd><br /></dd>	
			<dt>JSON-PESC XSLT</dt>
			<dd>
				JSON-PESC XSLT 3.4+ support <a href="https://github.com/nsip/sifxml2pescjson"> (GitHub Repository)</a>
			</dd>
			<!-- Leave this out when examples inline
			<dt>JSON-PESC Examples 3.4.6</dt>
			<dd>
				JSON-PESC Examples 3.4.6<a href="JSON/siftest.pretty.json"> (json)</a>
			</dd> -->
			<dt>OpenAPI</dt>
			<dd>
				<a href="JSON/OpenAPI.zip">OpenAPI &amp; JSON Schemas Files Archive</a>
			</dd>


		</dl>
		<p>Please refer to the <a href="errata/">errata</a> for this document, which may include some normative corrections.</p>
		<p>This document is also available in these non-normative formats: <a href="ImplementationSpecification.zip">ZIP archive</a>, <a href="ImplementationSpecification.pdf">PDF (for printing as a single file)</a>,
		<a href="ImplementationSpecification.xls">Excel spreadsheet</a>.</p>
		<br />
		<br />
		<p>Copyright ©2024 <a href="http://www.sifassociation.org">
				Systems Interoperability Framework (SIF™) Association</a>.  All Rights Reserved.
		</p>
	</TitlePage>
	
	<!--Preamble-->
	<Section name="Preamble" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="http://sifassociation.org/SpecGen" xml:base="01_Preamble/Infrastructure-Preamble.xml">

	<Section name="Abstract">
		<Section name="What is SIF?">
			<p>SIF is not a product, but a technical blueprint for enabling diverse applications to interact and share data related to entities in the pK-12 instructional and administrative environment. SIF is designed to:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Facilitate data sharing and reporting between applications without incurring expensive customer development costs;</li>
				<li>Enhance product functionality efficiently; and</li>
				<li>Provide best-of-breed solutions to customers easily and seamlessly.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>The SIF Implementation Specification defines common data formats and rules of interaction and architecture, and is made up of two parts:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>1. The <em>SIF Infrastructure</em> Implementation Specification which defines the rules of interaction and messages framework, and;</li>
				<li>2. The <em>SIF Data Model</em> Implementation Specification which is an XML-based data model that models entities in the learning environment as SIF Data Objects to be shared between applications;  This document only describes the SIF Data Model for Australia.</li>
			</ul>
			
	<p><em>SIF 3 Infrastructure defines;</em></p>
	<ul>
	<li>a secure REST-based transport protocol for defining both direct and brokered connections between software applications (which can act as REST servers or clients)</li>
	<li>a set of services to enable interactions between REST servers and clients, including creating environments, other administrative task, synchronous exchanges of data, and asynchronous message queues</li>
	<li>an abstract, platform-independent definition of the API between one software application and another or a broker.</li>
	</ul>
	
	<ul>
	<li>A <em>SIF Environment</em> is a distributed system that consists of one or more software applications with a SIF Adapter (a SIF-enabled application) sharing/reporting one or more SIF data objects over a network; it may also involve middleware (a message broker). A <em>SIF Implementation</em> consists of one or more SIF Environments deployed and configured to meet customer data sharing and reporting needs.</li>	
	
	<li>The SIF Implementation Specification defines architecture requirements and communication protocols for software components and the interfaces between them; it makes no assumption of specific hardware or software products needed to develop SIF-enabled applications and/or middleware implementations, other than their ability to support technologies leveraged as the foundation for SIF, most prominently XML and HTTP(S) and including JSON and REST.</li>
	</ul>

	
		<Section name="What is SIF (AU)?" xmlns="http://sifassociation.org/SpecGen">
  <p>
    SIF Implementation Specification (Australia) defines a set of data objects supporting Australia's interoperability
    requirements for the education sector and combines this data model with established infrastructure protocols from the SIF Implementation Specification <a href="References.html#SIF">[SIF]</a>.
    SIF Implementation Specification (Australia) 3 leverages the SIF architecture and refers to SIF Infrastructure Specifications greater than 3.0.1 [SIF 3.x]  to support its data objects, with an Australia-specific namespace and the data objects defined in this specification.
    Technical readers should note that the version number internal to SIF XML messages identifies the version number of the SIF Data Model.
  </p>
</Section>

	
	
	
		</Section>
		<Section name="SIF Association">
			<p>The Schools Interoperability Framework Association (SIF Association); known in Australia as; The Systems Interoperability Framework Association, is an industry initiative to enable interoperability and data sharing between
		software applications in the pK-12 instructional and administrative environment, and the forum for companies and educators to participate 
		in the development of SIF specifications in the SIF Association's working groups and task forces.  The SIF Association is designed to:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Join industry leaders in creating the next-generation framework for education technology; and</li>
				<li>Leverage co-marketing opportunities with partners and distributors.</li>
			</ul>
		</Section>
	</Section>
	<Section name="Disclaimer">
		<p>The information, software, products, and services included
in the SIF Implementation Specification may include inaccuracies or typographical errors. Changes are periodically added to the information herein. The SIF Association may make improvements and/or changes in this document at any time without notification. Information contained in this document should not be relied upon for personal, medical, legal, or financial decisions. Appropriate professionals should be consulted for advice tailored to specific situations.</p>
		<p>THE SIF ASSOCIATION, ITS PARTICIPANT(S), AND THIRD PARTY CONTENT PROVIDERS MAKE NO REPRESENTATIONS ABOUT THE SUITABILITY, RELIABILITY, TIMELINESS, AND ACCURACY OF THE INFORMATION, SOFTWARE, PRODUCTS, SERVICES, AND RELATED GRAPHICS CONTAINED IN THIS DOCUMENT FOR ANY PURPOSE. ALL SUCH INFORMATION, SOFTWARE, PRODUCTS, SERVICES, AND RELATED GRAPHICS ARE PROVIDED "AS IS" WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND. THE SIF ASSOCIATION AND/OR ITS PARTICIPANT(S) HEREBY DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS WITH REGARD TO THIS INFORMATION, SOFTWARE, PRODUCTS, SERVICES, AND RELATED GRAPHICS, INCLUDING ALL IMPLIED WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, TITLE, AND NON-INFRINGEMENT.</p>
		<p>IN NO EVENT SHALL THE SIF ASSOCIATION, ITS PARTICIPANT(S), OR THIRD PARTY CONTENT PROVIDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, PUNITIVE, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, OR ANY DAMAGES WHATSOEVER INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, DAMAGES FOR LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS, ARISING OUT OF OR IN ANY WAY CONNECTED WITH THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF THIS DOCUMENT, WITH THE DELAY OR INABILITY TO USE THE DOCUMENT, THE PROVISION OF OR FAILURE TO PROVIDE SERVICES, OR FOR ANY INFORMATION, SOFTWARE, PRODUCTS, SERVICES AND RELATED GRAPHICS OBTAINED THROUGH THIS DOCUMENT OR OTHERWISE ARISING OUT OF THE USE OF THIS DOCUMENT, WHETHER BASED ON CONTRACT, TORT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR OTHERWISE, EVEN IF THE SIF ASSOCIATION, ITS PARTICIPANT(S), OR THIRD PARTY CONTENT PROVIDERS HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF DAMAGES. BECAUSE SOME STATES/JURISDICTIONS DO NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OR LIMITATION OF LIABILITY FOR CONSEQUENTIAL OR INCIDENTAL DAMAGES, THE ABOVE LIMITATION MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU. IF YOU ARE DISSATISFIED WITH ANY PORTION OF THIS DOCUMENT OR WITH ANY OF THESE TERMS OF USE, YOUR SOLE AND EXCLUSIVE REMEDY IS TO DISCONTINUE USING THIS DOCUMENT.</p>
	</Section>
	<p>This specification is released with the following provisos to developers and educators.</p>
	<Section name="Certification and Compliance Claims">
		<p>
        Though a product may be demonstrated to comply with this specification, no product may be designated as 
        <em>SIF Certified™</em> by an organization
        or individual until the product has been tested against and
        passed established compliance criteria, published separately <a href="References.html#SIFCertification">[SIFCertification]</a>.  
				Organizations and individuals that are currently paying annual membership dues to the SIF Association 
        and dedicating resources to the initiative may also use the designation
        <em>SIF Participant</em> to describe their involvement with the SIF Association and SIF in marketing, public relations and other materials.
    </p>
	</Section>
	<Section name="Permissions and Copyright">
		<p>	® Copyright Access 4 Learning Community. Some Rights Reserved.</p>
		<Section name="Overview"> 
		<p>On July 18th, 2017 the Access 4 Learning Community (henceforth “A4L”) Association Board of Directors elected to ensure that the contents, associated artifacts and  schemas representing the SIF specification should be open and available to all and protected under global standard licensing agreements.</p> 
		<p>All human-readable artifacts published and created by the Access 4 Learning Community are protected under a Creative Commons license.</p> 
		<p>All machine-readable artifacts and content is protected under an Apache 2 license.</p>  
		<p>All published artifacts and Specifications published after July 18, 2017 are covered.</p>
		</Section>
		<Section name="Human-readable artifacts">
		<p>The SIF Implementation Specifications and all human-readable related artifacts and materials are available under an <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">Attribution-ShareAlike CC BY-SA 4.0</a> International license. Entities must give appropriate credit, provide a link to the license, and indicate if changes were made. Modifications of this license and derivatives need to be licensed under the same terms, but not other works in the compilation or collection. You may do so in any reasonable manner, but not in any way that suggests the licensor endorses you or your use. If you remix, transform, or build upon the material, you must distribute your contributions under the same license as the original. Entities may not apply legal terms or technological measures that legally restrict others from doing anything the license permits.</p>
		<p><a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/"><img decoding="async" src="https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/buttons/88x31/png/by-sa.png" width="117" height="41" align="right" /></a><em>This license enables reusers to distribute, remix, adapt, and build upon the material in any medium or format, so long as attribution is given to the creator. The license allows for commercial use. If you remix, adapt, or build upon the material, you must license the modified material under identical terms.</em></p>
		</Section>
		<Section name="Machine-readable artifacts">
		<p><a href="https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0.html"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.apache.org/foundation/press/kit/asf_logo_small.png" height="50" width="125" align="right" /></a>The machine-readable files associated with the Specification, including Excel presentations, XSD schemas, JSON schemas, and OpenAPI specifications, are all licensed under the <a href="https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0.html">Apache 2.0</a> license.  Developers can look here for guidance on using the license: <a href="https://www.apache.org/legal/apply-license.html">Using the Apache license</a>.   The Apache 2.0 License is permissive. It allows you to use, modify, and distribute the licensed software, including creating derivative works, without requiring those derivative works to be licensed under the same terms. You can release the modified parts of the code under any license you prefer.</p>
		</Section>
	</Section>
</Section>

	
	<!--Introduction-->
	<Section name="Introduction" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="http://sifassociation.org/SpecGen" xml:base="02_Introduction/Introduction-Datamodel.xml">
  <Section name="Specification Organization">
    <p>
      With respect to the SIF Specification, educators and non-technical readers are typically interested in the pK-12 data objects
      that can be shared and reported on by SIF-enabled applications in SIF implementations.  This document, the <em>SIF Data Model Implementation Specification</em>, contains a <a href="DataModel.html">Data Model</a>
      section in a format that should not be a barrier to readers with some knowledge of <a href="http://https://www.w3.org/XML/">[XML]</a>.
      More technical readers, including software architects,
      developers and integrators, will also be interested in the separate <em>SIF Infrastructure Implementation Specification</em> document.   
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>
        The <a href="index.html#Preamble">Preamble</a> provides an abstract of SIF along with the SIF Association disclaimer and details regarding certification and compliance claims.
      </li>
      <li>
        This Introduction outlines the organization of this specification document, provides conventions used in this document, and summarizes versioning of the specification.
        Highlights of additions/changes since the previous version of the specification are also provided.
      </li>
      <li>
        The <a href="DataModel.html">Data Model</a> section provides definitions of the XML structure for common elements in the data model and all objects
        related to entities in the pK-12 environment.  This section is organized by the working groups and task forces within the SIF Association that have defined
        common elements or objects.
      </li>
      <li>
        The document concludes with various appendices including lists of code set values defined within SIF and in external documents,
        and ends with a list of <a href="References.html">references</a> to other documents.
      </li>
    </ul>
  </Section>
  <Section name="Document Conventions">
    <Section name="Definitions">
      <p>
        The first time a term or concept is defined, it may be <em>emphasized</em>.
      </p>
    </Section>
    <Section name="Structure and Values">
      <p>
        <code>SIF message and object names, XML element tags, attribute names and values, and other codes or values are typically presented as in this sentence.</code>
      </p>
    </Section>
    <Section name="Examples">
      <Example name="Examples Convention">Longer examples of XML,JSON or HTTP messages are typically numbered and presented as given here.</Example>
    </Section>
    
    <Section name="JSON">
      <p>Java Script Object Notation (<em>JSON</em>) is an alternate way to represent an object in a tree like structure. <em>JSON</em> is desirable for a variety of reasons including: good wire efficiency, strong programming support, and satisfactory human readability. Since SIF’s data models are formally defined using XML Schemas, <em>JSON</em> conversion is handled through one of two sets of rules. </p>
<p><code>Default: </code><em>Goessner Notation</em>, which uses schema-independent generic rules for ease of translation. <a href="https://www.xml.com/pub/a/2006/05/31/converting-between-xml-and-json.html">[Goessner JSON]</a></p>
<p>
<code>Preferred: </code><em>PESC JSON</em> which uses schema-aware rules for consistent results. <a href="http://specification.sifassociation.org/Implementation/Infrastructure/3.3/PESC_JSON.pdf">[PESC JSON]</a>
</p>
    </Section> 
    <Section name="References">
      <p>
        References to other works occurring in this text are given in brackets, e.g. [REFERENCE].  The text in brackets corresponds to a key in the <a href="References.html#References">References</a> appendix.
        Often when the text in the brackets duplicates surrounding text, the reference alone is used (e.g. [XML] instead of XML [XML]).
      </p>
    </Section>
    <Section name="Terminology">
      <p>
        The key words <span class="rfc2119">MUST</span>, <span class="rfc2119">MUST NOT</span>, <span class="rfc2119">REQUIRED</span>, <span class="rfc2119">SHALL</span>,
        <span class="rfc2119">SHALL NOT</span>, <span class="rfc2119">SHOULD</span>, <span class="rfc2119">SHOULD NOT</span>, <span class="rfc2119">RECOMMENDED</span>,
        <span class="rfc2119">MAY</span>, <span class="rfc2119">OPTIONAL</span>, when <span class="rfc2119">EMPHASIZED</span>, are to be interpreted as described in <a href="https://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc2119.txt">[RFC 2119]</a>.
      </p>
    </Section>
    <Section name="XML Diagrams">
      <p>
        Quick overviews of XML structures, including messages, objects, common elements and types, are provided in XML diagrams.  The following diagram illustrates
        the conventions typically encountered in SIF.
      </p>
      <p>
        <img src="images/SequenceElement.png" title="XML Diagram Conventions" />
      </p>
      <p>
        XML elements are represented by rectangles with the name of the element in the upper portion and the type, if any, in the lower portion.  Attributes
        are represented in the same fashion, but have an <code>@</code> icon rather than a SIF icon.  Elements and attributes that are optional have a circled <code>?</code>
        (0 or 1 occurrence) to the left of the rectangle.  Optional and mandatory repeatable elements are indicated by a circled <code>*</code> (0 or more occurrences)
        and <code>+</code> (1 or more occurrences), respectively.
        Element attributes are grouped together in a rectangular block and connected to the element with a line that turns at right angles.
        Ordered sequences of XML elements are bracketed by lines that turn at right angles.  When a choice of XML elements is indicated, the elements are bracketed by angled
        lines.  A choice of elements can occur within an element, or may be an unnamed choice of elements.
      </p>
      <p>XML types are represented using the same conventions as for XML elements, though the type portion of the rectangle typically indicates a base type, if any.</p>
      <p>
        The type name of any element, attribute or type may be prefixed with a <code>↓</code>, indicating the type is restricted in some fashion by one or more
        XML Schema facets (e.g. enumeration).  When the type is a union of types, a list of types is presented, each type separated by <code>|</code>; if the list of union types
        is long, the list may be marked with ellipses, e.g., <code>| ...</code>
      </p>
      <p>In an actual XML diagram, element, type and attribute rectangles are usually linked to their corresponding definitions/descriptions in accompanying tables.</p>
    </Section>
  </Section>
  <Section name="Version Numbers">
    <p>The SIF Implementation Specification uses the following version numbering scheme:</p>

    <p>
      <em>major version</em>
      <code>.</code>
      <em>minor version</em>
      <code>.</code>
      <em>revision number</em>
      <Code>(X.Y.Z)</Code>
    </p>
    <p>Once a versioned specification (Specification Release) has been released, the contents of that version MUST NOT be modified. Any modifications MUST be released under a new Specification Version Number unless the modification is the correction of an error or update of documentation. Each Specification Release has an associated errata section in which modifications and corrections of the release are listed.</p>
    <p>A Specification Version Number for a Specification Release uses conventions as follows:  

	<ul>
	<li>A Specification Version Number MAY take the form <Code>X.Y.Z</Code> where <Code>X</Code>, <Code>Y</Code>, and <Code>Z</Code> are nonnegative integers (whole numbers), and MUST NOT contain leading zeroes. <Code>X</Code> represents the <em>Major version</em>, <Code>Y</Code>  represents the <em>Minor version</em>, and <Code>Z</Code> represents the <em>Revision version</em>.</li>
	<li>Each version number element MUST increase sequentially based on the guidelines defined within this document; for instance, <Code>1.9.1</Code> to <Code>1.10</Code> to <Code>1.11</Code> to <Code>1.11.1</Code> .</li>
	<li>Precedence refers to how versions are compared to each other when ordered. Precedence MUST be calculated by separating the version into major, minor, revision identifiers in that order. Precedence is determined by the first difference when comparing each of these identifiers from left to right as follows: Major, Minor, and Revision versions are always compared numerically; for example, <Code>1.0.0</Code> &lt; <Code>2.0.0</Code> &lt; <Code>2.1.0</Code> &lt; <Code>2.1.1</Code> .</li>
	</ul>

</p>
<p>An instance of a Specification Version Number is the canonical identifier for a Specification Release. The manner in which the Specification Version Number increments after a given Specification Release depends on the type and relative magnitude of changes being proposed in the new release as follows:
</p>
<p>
1.	The Revision version number ( <Code>Z</Code> in <em>x.y.</em><Code>Z</Code>, where <Code>x</Code> &gt;= 0) MUST be incremented when specification changes are limited to backward compatible changes. If <Code>Z</Code>=0 then the convention is to drop the Revision number: for example, <Code>3.1</Code> instead of <Code>3.1.0</Code>. Backward compatible changes include the following:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>New data object.</li>
    <li>New optional data object element.</li>
	<li>New optional utility service object element.</li>
</ul>
    <p>2.	The Minor version number ( <Code>Y</Code> in <em>x.</em><Code>Y</Code><em>.z</em>, where <Code>x</Code> &gt; 0 ) MUST be incremented if new functionality is added to the specification. It MUST be incremented if any aspect of the specification is marked as deprecated. It MUST be incremented if any aspect of the specification is not backward compatible. (Backward compatible means any change that can be implemented by one participant (consumer, Environment or service provider) without requiring changes by other participants to maintaining the same level of interoperability.)  It MAY be incremented if substantial new functionality or improvements are introduced. It MAY include changes that are categorized as ”Revision” level magnitude. The Revision version MUST be reset to 0 when the Minor version is incremented. Changes requiring a Minor version increment include the following:  
    </p>
   <ul>
<li>New mandatory data object element.</li>	 
<li>New mandatory utility service object element.</li> 
<li>Deprecate data object element.</li> 
<li>Deprecate data object.</li> 
<li>Deprecate utility service object element.</li> 
<li>Deprecate utility service object.</li>
<li>Remove deprecated data object element.</li> 
<li>Remove deprecated data object.</li>
<li>Remove deprecated utility service object element.</li> 
<li>Remove deprecated utility service object.</li>
<li>Add support for additional authentication methods.</li> 
<li>Add support for additional TLS version. </li>
<li>Any changes concerning security.</li> 
<li>Any optional to mandatory change.</li> 
<li>Add support for additional payload representations.</li> 
</ul>

    <p>3.	The Major version number ( <Code>X</Code> in <Code>X</Code><em>.y.z</em>, where <Code>X</Code> &gt; 0 ) MUST be incremented if a significant change is introduced to the specification. It MAY include changes categorized as Minor and Revision level changes. The Revision and Minor version numbers MUST be reset to 0 when the Major version is incremented. Changes requiring a Major version increment include the following:
    <ul> 
<li>Deprecate payload representation.</li>	 
<li>Remove deprecated payload representation.</li> 
<li>Add support for a distinct data model namespace.</li> 
<li>Replace (deprecate and remove) a locale data model.</li> 
<li>Any significant change that requires the Major version to be incremented as deemed by the A4L Association Board for global specifications and Management Boards for locale data models.</li> 
</ul>

    </p>
  </Section>
  <Section name="Highlighted Additions/Changes" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="http://sifassociation.org/SpecGen">
	
	<p>This release contains the following significant updates and extensions to the SIF specification.</p>
	<h3>Additions/Changes since 3.6.2 June, 2024</h3>

	<h4>New Inclusions</h4>
	<ul>
	<li>None.</li>
	</ul>

	<h4>New Objects</h4>
	<ul>
	<li>None.</li>
	</ul>
	
	<h4>Removed Objects</h4>
	<ul>
	<li>None.</li>
	</ul>


	<h4>New Elements</h4>
	<u