<Section name="Introduction" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Section name="Specification Organization">
    <p>
      With respect to the SIF Specification, educators and non-technical readers are typically interested in the pK-12 data objects
      that can be shared and reported on by SIF-enabled applications in SIF implementations.  This document, the <em>SIF Data Model Implementation Specification</em>, contains a <a href="DataModel.html">Data Model</a>
      section in a format that should not be a barrier to readers with a some knowledge of <a href="http://www.w3.org/XML/1999/XML-in-10-points.html">[XML]</a>.
      More technical readers, including software architects,
      developers and integrators, will also be interested in the separate <em>SIF Infrastructure Implementation Specification</em> document.   
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>
        The <a href="index.html#Preamble">Preamble</a> provides an abstract of SIF along with the SIF Association disclaimer and details regarding certification and compliance claims.
      </li>
      <li>
        This Introduction outlines the organization of this specification document, provides conventions used in this document, and summarizes versioning of the specification.
        Highlights of additions/changes since the previous version of the specification are also provided.
      </li>
      <li>
        The <a href="DataModel.html">Data Model</a> section provides definitions of the XML structure for common elements in the data model and all objects
        related to entities in the pK-12 environment.  This section is organized by the working groups and task forces within the SIF Association that have defined
        common elements or objects.
      </li>
      <li>
		  <a href="ZoneServices.html">Zone Services</a> details the data formats and operation choreographies of the interfaces which Zone Services provide in support of their clients.
      </li>
      <li>
        The document concludes with various appendices including lists of code set values defined within SIF and in external documents,
        and ends with a list of <a href="References.html">references</a> to other documents.
      </li>
    </ul>
  </Section>
  <Section name="Document Conventions">
    <Section name="Definitions">
      <p>
        The first time a term or concept is defined, it may be <em>emphasized</em>.
      </p>
    </Section>
    <Section name="Structure and Values">
      <p>
        <code>SIF message and object names, XML element tags, attribute names and values, and other codes or values are typically presented as in this sentence.</code>
      </p>
    </Section>
    <Section name="Examples">
      <Example name="Examples Convention">Longer examples of XML or HTTP messages are typically numbered and presented as given here.</Example>
    </Section>
    <Section name="References">
      <p>
        References to other works occurring in this text are given in brackets, e.g. [REFERENCE].  The text in brackets corresponds to a key in the <a href="References.html#References">References</a> appendix.
        Often when the text in the brackets duplicates surrounding text, the reference alone is used (e.g. [XML] instead of XML [XML]).
      </p>
    </Section>
    <Section name="Terminology">
      <p>
        The key words <span class="rfc2119">MUST</span>, <span class="rfc2119">MUST NOT</span>, <span class="rfc2119">REQUIRED</span>, <span class="rfc2119">SHALL</span>,
        <span class="rfc2119">SHALL NOT</span>, <span class="rfc2119">SHOULD</span>, <span class="rfc2119">SHOULD NOT</span>, <span class="rfc2119">RECOMMENDED</span>,
        <span class="rfc2119">MAY</span>, <span class="rfc2119">OPTIONAL</span>, when <span class="rfc2119">EMPHASIZED</span>, are to be interpreted as described in <a href="References.html#RFC2119">[RFC 2119]</a>.
      </p>
    </Section>
    <Section name="XML Diagrams">
      <p>
        Quick overviews of XML structures, including messages, objects, common elements and types, are provided in XML diagrams.  The following diagram illustrates
        the conventions typically encountered in SIF.
      </p>
      <p>
        <img src="images/SequenceElement.png" title="XML Diagram Conventions"/>
      </p>
      <p>
        XML elements are represented by rectangles with the name of the element in the upper portion and the type, if any, in the lower portion.  Attributes
        are represented in the same fashion, but have an <code>@</code> icon rather than a SIF icon.  Elements and attributes that are optional have a circled <code>?</code>
        (0 or 1 occurrence) to the left of the rectangle.  Optional and mandatory repeatable elements are indicated by a circled <code>*</code> (0 or more occurrences)
        and <code>+</code> (1 or more occurrences), respectively.
        Element attributes are grouped together in a rectangular block and connected to the element with a line that turns at right angles.
        Ordered sequences of XML elements are bracketed by lines that turn at right angles.  When a choice of XML elements is indicated, the elements are bracketed by angled
        lines.  A choice of elements can occur within an element, or may be an unnamed choice of elements.
      </p>
      <p>XML types are represented using the same conventions as for XML elements, though the type portion of the rectangle typically indicates a base type, if any.</p>
      <p>
        The type name of any element, attribute or type may be prefixed with a <code>&#x2193;</code>, indicating the type is restricted in some fashion by one or more
        XML Schema facets (e.g. enumeration).  When the type is a union of types, a list of types is presented, each type separated by <code>|</code>; if the list of union types
        is long, the list may be marked with ellipses, e.g., <code>| ...</code>
      </p>
      <p>In an actual XML diagram, element, type and attribute rectangles are usually linked to their corresponding definitions/descriptions in accompanying tables.</p>
    </Section>
  </Section>
  <Section name="Version Numbers">
    <p>The SIF Implementation Specification uses the following version numbering scheme:</p>

    <p>
      <em>major version</em>
      <code>.</code>
      <em>minor version</em>
      <code>r</code>
      <em>revision number</em>
    </p>

    <p>
      Major versions typically introduce additions/changes to the SIF infrastructure and/or data model changes that impact a significant
      percentage of SIF-enabled applications (e.g. making previously optional elements mandatory, removal of deprecated objects, elements or values).
      The first release of a major version has a minor version of <code>0</code> (<code>2.0</code>);
      major version numbers start at <code>1</code> and are incremented as major versions are released (<code>1.0</code>, <code>2.0</code>, <code>3.0</code>, ...).
    </p>

    <p>
      Minor releases typically introduce new data objects, or optional additions to data objects, to the marketplace, and may include minor
      infrastructure additions/changes that do not impact existing SIF-enabled applications and that ZIS vendors have agreed to implement.
      The first minor version released subsequent
      to and within a major release has a minor version of <code>1</code> and is incremented as new minor versions are released
      (<code>2.1</code>, <code>2.2</code>, ...).  If a significant number of minor release features is introduced in a specification,
      the SIF Association may decide to increment the minor version number by more than <code>1</code> (e.g. <code>1.1</code> to <code>1.5</code>),
      though a number like <code>1.5</code> is not an indication of being halfway to a major release, as minor version numbers may be incremented
      significantly past <code>10</code> (<code>2.10</code>, <code>2.11</code>, ...) as data objects and other minor version features are released.
    </p>

    <p>
      Corrections resulting from identified errata, as well as textual changes, may be incorporated into a revision release.
      These typically include minor corrections to messages or data objects, corrections of typographical errors, or corrected/expanded documentation.
      If major errors in any release are identified, a revision release may incorporate changes more typical of a major or minor release.
      First major and minor releases have a revision number of <code>0</code>, which is omitted from the version number (<code>2.0</code>, not <code>2.0r0</code>);
      subsequent revision numbers start at <code>1</code> and are incremented as new revisions are released (<code>2.0r1</code>, <code>2.0r2</code>,
      ...).
    </p>
  </Section>
  <xi:include parse="text" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="custom/ChangeLog-Datamodel.xml"/>
</Section>