
<IncludeGroup
	xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
	
 	xmlns="http://sifassociation.org/SpecGen">

	<CodeSet>
		<Intro>
			<p>
				Describes classes of address as recognised by Land Information NZ.
			</p>
		</Intro>
		<ID>Address Type</ID>
		<Values>
			<Value>
				<Code>1</Code>
				<Text>Thoroughfare</Text>
				<Description>
					<p>Also called 'Street' addresses, The most
					general, and widely used type of address, and can
					contain the widest variety of components.</p>
					
					<p>In general a thoroughfare address will include
					components for a number, a roadname, and a
					locality.</p>
					
					<p>They cannot contain any of the components
					specific to a delivery service, rural post
					delivery, or water address.</p>
					
					<p>These addresses are used to find a location.</p>
					<p><em>Example:</em> 30 - 40 Lambton Quay, Wellington, 6165</p>
				</Description>
			</Value>
			<Value>
				<Code>2</Code>
				<Text>Rural</Text>
				<Description>
					<p>Defined by New Zealand Post, these addresses
					are assigned by NZ Post for customers who purchase
					a rural delivery service (mail and also other
					goods).</p>

					<p>They will have the same number and roadname
					components as the street address, and may have the
					same region component.</p>
					
					<p>They do not have a component that identifies
					the locality the address is within. The locality
					and city or town components are replaced by
					components that identify the rural delivery route
					(RD number), and the town from which the rural
					delivery route starts and finishes (the mail
					town). Only addresses of this class can contain
					these components.
					</p>

					<p><em>Example:</em> 121 Waitaha Road, RD 1, Ross, 7885</p>
				</Description>
			</Value>
			
			<!-- Includes P O Box, Pvt Bag, CMB, etc. -->
			<Value>
				<Code>3</Code>
				<Text>Delivery Service</Text>
				<Description>
					<p>Defined by New Zealand Post, and used
					exclusively for NZ Post services other than
					standard mail delivery. Addresses in this class
					include PO Box, Private Bag, and Counter Delivery
					addresses.</p>

					<p><em>Example:</em> Private Bag 2345, Auckland, 1142</p>
				</Description>
			</Value>

			<Value>
				<Code>4</Code>
				<Text>Water</Text>
				<Description>
					<p>Where properties have no road access, but do
					have access to water frontage (coastline or
					riverbank or lakefront), a water address uses the
					name of a water feature (for example, islands,
					rivers, bays, or peninsulas).</p>

					<p><em>Example:</em> 235 Lochmara Bay, Queen Charlotte Sound, Marlborough Sounds</p>
				</Description>
			</Value>
			
			<Value>
				<Code>5</Code>
				<Text>Foreign Addres</Text>
				<Description>
					<p>A foreign address identifies a location outside of New Zealand.</p>
					<p><em>Example:</em> Rudolf-Diesel-Strasse 14, 54595 Prüm, Germany</p>
				</Description>
			</Value>
		</Values>
	</CodeSet>    <!-- NZ Address Type -->
	<CodeSet>
		<Intro>
			<p>Describes what a particular address is used for.</p>
		</Intro>
		<ID>Address Role</ID>
		<Values>
			<Value>
				<Code>1</Code>
				<Text>Residental Address</Text>
			</Value>
			<Value>
				<Code>2</Code>
				<Text>Postal Address</Text>
			</Value>
		</Values>
	</CodeSet>    <!-- NZ Address Role -->
	<CodeSet>
		<Intro>
			<p>Describes a spatial unit defined by Stats NZ.</p>
		</Intro>
		<ID>Spatial Unit Type</ID>
		<Values>
			<Value>
				<Code>AE</Code>
				<Text>Area Unit</Text>
				<Description>
					<p> Area units are aggregations of
					meshblocks. They are non–administrative areas that
					are in between meshblocks and territorial
					authorities in size. Area units must either define
					or aggregate to define, regional councils,
					territorial authorities and urban areas.</p>
				</Description>
			</Value>
			<Value>
				<Code>GE</Code>
				<Text>General Electoral Distric</Text>
				<Description>
					<p>The general electoral districts as constituted under the Electoral Act 1993.</p>
				</Description>
			</Value>
			<Value>
				<Code>CB</Code>
				<Text>Community Board</Text>
				<Description>
					<p>(aka Local Board within Auckland) Local boards
					provide governance at the local level within
					Auckland Council. They enable democratic decision
					making by, and on behalf of communities within the
					local board area.</p>
				</Description>
			</Value>
			<Value>
				<Code>ME</Code>
				<Text>Māori Electoral District</Text>
				<Description>
					<p>Māori electoral districts are the voting
					districts for parliamentary elections for people
					who choose to be on the Māori Electoral Roll.</p>
				</Description>
			</Value>
			<Value>
				<Code>MB</Code>
				<Text>Mesh Block</Text>
				<Description>
					<p>A meshblock is the smallest geographic unit for
					which statistical data is collected and processed
					by Statistics New Zealand.</p>
					<p>A meshblock is defined by a geographic area,
					which can vary in size from part of a city block
					to a large area of rural land. Each meshblock
					borders on another to form a network covering all
					of New Zealand, including coasts and inlets and
					extending out to the 200-mile economic zone.</p>
				</Description>
			</Value>
			<Value>
				<Code>RC</Code>
				<Text>Regional Council</Text>
				<Description>
					<p>The top tier of local government in New Zealand, defined
					by the Local Government Act 2002, which requires the
					boundaries of regions to conform as far as
					possible to one or more water catchments. When
					determining regional boundaries, the Local
					Government Commission gave consideration to
					regional communities of interest when selecting
					water catchments to be included in a region. It
					also considered factors such as natural resource
					management, land use planning and environmental
					matters.</p>
				</Description>
			</Value>
			<Value>
				<Code>TA</Code>
				<Text>Territorial Authority</Text>
				<Description>
					<p>The second tier of local government in New
					Zealand, defined under the Local Government Act
					2002 as a city council or district council. There
					are 67 territorial authorities consisting of 12
					city councils, 53 districts, Auckland Council, and
					Chatham Islands Council.</p>
				</Description>
			</Value>
			<Value>
				<Code>UA</Code>
				<Text>Urban Area</Text>
				<Description>
					<p>Urban Areas are statistically defined areas
					with no administrative or legal basis. There is a
					three part hierarchical sub-division of urban
					areas into: main urban areas, secondary urban
					areas, minor urban areas.  Together the
					populations in main, secondary and minor urban
					areas comprise the statistically defined urban
					population of New Zealand. The urban area
					classification is designed to identify
					concentrated urban or semi-urban settlements
					without the distortions of administrative
					boundaries.</p>
				</Description>
			</Value>
			<Value>
				<Code>WA</Code>
				<Text>Ward</Text>
				<Description>
					<p>Wards are defined under the Local Electoral Act
					2001 and result from the division, for electoral
					purposes, of the district of a territorial
					authority.  The ward system was designed to allow
					for the recognition of communities within a
					district and to increase community involvement in
					the local government system.</p>
				</Description>
			</Value>
		</Values>
	</CodeSet>    <!-- NZ Spatial Unit Type -->
	
</IncludeGroup>
