<Section name="Highlighted Additions/Changes"
		 xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
		 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		 xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
		 
         xmlns="http://sifassociation.org/SpecGen">
	
	<p>This release contains the following significant updates and extensions to the SIF specification.</p>
	<h3>Additions/Changes since 3.4.6 (March, 2020)</h3>
	<h4>New Objects</h4>
	<ul>
		<li>AddressCollection - Object for Australian Government collection submission collecting addresses of students from schools and school authorities</li>
		<li>CensusCollection - Object for Australian Government collection submission collecting non-government school census information from schools and school authorities.</li>
		<li>CollectionRound - Object reporting the rounds available for submission of a particular Australian Government (AG) Collection. Object is published by the Australian Government Schools hub.</li>
		<li>CollectionStatus - Object reporting the processing status of a collection object submitted to the Australian Government. Object is published by the Australian Government collections hub.</li>
		<li>FinancialQuestionnaireCollection - Object for Australian Government collection submission collecting financial information from schools and school authorities.</li>
		<li>StudentAttendanceCollection - Object for Australian Government collection submission collecting Student Attendance Information. The Student Attendance Collection captures attendance information for each school location by cohort. A cohort comprises the combination of year level, gender and indigeneity. There are a maximum of six possible cohorts per year level (see Cohort attribute in table below). Data is submitted to the collection at two reporting periods (Semester 1 and Term 3). Student Attendance data is only captured for full-time students in Years 1 to 10.</li>
		<li>LibraryPatronStatus - This object reports the current library status for the requested student or staff member. </li>
	</ul>
		<h4>New Types</h4>
	<ul>
		<li>Added for LibraryPatronStatus - LibraryTransactionListType, LibraryTransactionType, LibraryItemInfoType, CheckoutInfoType, FineInfoListType, FineInfoType, HoldInfoListType, HoldInfoType, LibraryMessageListType, LibraryMessageType </li>
		<li>Added for all AG Collection Objects CollectionReportingListTypes</li>
	</ul>
	
	<h4>New Enumerations</h4>
	<h4>Additions to CodeSets</h4>
	
	<ul>	
		<li>Addition to Year Level Code- 0 Year Level 0 - added for AG Collections</li>	
		<li>Addition to Relationship to Student - 14 Step-Sibling - added for NSW - school request</li>	
		<li>Additions to Attendance Codes for COVID-19 - request from VIC DET - 625 Remote learning and 214 Sent home (COVID symptoms)</li>	

	</ul>

	<h4>Other Changes</h4>
	<ul>
		<li>Federal Electorate Codeset - Wakefield Deprecated</li>
		<li>StudentPersonal- MostRecent - CensusAge Integer</li>
 	</ul>
   	
	
</Section>
