<Section name="Highlighted Additions/Changes"
		 xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
		 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		 xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
		 
         xmlns="http://sifassociation.org/SpecGen">
	
	<p>This release contains the following significant updates and extensions to the SIF specification.</p>
	<h3>Additions/Changes since 3.4.7 August, 2020)</h3>
	<h4>New Objects</h4>
	<ul>
		<li>No new objects were added for this release</li>
	</ul>
	<h4>New Elements</h4>
	<ul>
		<li>Deceased Flag – to indicate deceased status of a person at request of CEM.</li>
		<li>Travel Mode to StudentSchoolEnrollment</li>
	</ul>
	
	<h4>New Types</h4>
	<ul>
	<li>New Types: a) HomeRoomType b)StaffRefIdType added to correct Venetian Blind typing </li>
	<li>New Types for Venetian Blind typing of SystemRole and ResourceUseage Objects</li>
	<li>TravelDetailsContainerType and SchoolTravelType added to support CEM requirements around student travel arrangements.</li>
    </ul>
	<h4>New Enumerations</h4>
	<ul><li>New enumeration added to the Sex Code Set to represent Victorian legislation, value added;  4 - Self-described</li></ul>
	
	<h5>New CodeSets added to support CEM Travel mode additions</h5>
	<ul>	
		<li>Travel Mode - Introduced by CEM to indicate mode of travel of the student to/from school.</li>
		<li>Accompaniment - Introduced by CEM to indicate whether or not the student is accompanied to/from school.</li>
	</ul>

	<h4>Other Changes</h4>
	<ul>
		<li>FSystemRole and ResourceUsage Objects have been reformatted to Venetian Blind</li>
 	</ul>
   	
	<h4>Corrections</h4>
	<ul>
		<p>Several Types used in the AG Collections were changed to xs:unsignedInt as they are required to be positive integers.</p>
		<li>Stats Collection (Attendance) - DaysInReferencePeriod, PossibleSchoolDays, AttendanceLess90Percent,	AttendanceGTE90Percent, PossibleSchoolDaysGT90PercentAttendance </li>
		<li>Census collection: Student Reporting: Headcount, CensusAge;	Staff Reporting: Headcount; StudentSchoolEnrollment: CensusAge - was listed as a decimal, it is required to be a positive integer for AG reporting.</li>
        <p>Code set corrections were as follows:</p>
        <li>a) Correction of the description of NAP Jurisdiction enumerations.  Western Australia listed twice.  Code Set updated.</li>
        <li>b) Correction of ill-formed value in LearningStandardItem Relationship Types enumeration set.</li>

   </ul>
   <h4>Deletions</h4>
   <ul>
   <p>AG have requested the following deletions:</p>
   <li>AddressCollection: ReportingAuthorityCommonwealthId,	EntityLevel, SchoolInfoRefId, LocalId, StateProvinceId,	ACARAId</li>
   <li>CensusCollection:  ReportingAuthorityCommonwealthId,	EntityLevel </li>
   <li>FinancialQuestionnaireCollection:  ReportingAuthorityCommonwealthId,	EntityLevel, SchoolInfoRefId, LocalId, StateProvinceId, ACARAId </li>
   <li>StudentAttendanceCollection:	ReportingAuthorityCommonwealthId, EntityLevel, SchoolInfoRefId, LocalId, StateProvinceId, ACARAId</li>
   </ul>

</Section>
