<Section name="Highlighted Additions/Changes"
		 xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
		 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		 xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
		 
         xmlns="http://sifassociation.org/SpecGen">
	
	<p>This release contains the following significant updates and extensions to the SIF specification.</p>
	<h3>Additions/Changes since 3.5.0 December, 2022</h3>
	<!--
	<h4>New Objects</h4>
	<ul>
	</ul>
	
			<h4>Removed Objects</h4>
	<ul>
	</ul>-->


	<h4>New Elements</h4>
	<ul>
		<li><code>ScheduledActivity/TimeTableChangeReasonList</code>, requested by Timetabling Solutions,
		to provide rationale for timetabling change published through <code>ScheduledActivity</code>, and
		make it easier to process automatically.</li>
		<li><code>ScheduledActivity/OverridePatch</code>, 
		to indicate whether timetabling change published through <code>ScheduledActivity</code> is to be
		processed as patch (omitted elements are preserved) or put (omitted elements are deleted).</li>
		<li><code>Demographics/Gender</code>, to differentiate clearly between biological sex and
		gender identity, and to align naming to current practice throughout the country.</li>
	</ul>
	
	
	<h4>New Types</h4>
	<ul>
	<li><code>Domain Score SDTN Type</code>, to allow the NAPLAN domain scores for a student to be published
	as part of the Student Data Transfer Note payload while allowing more elements to be optional than for
	the output of the National Assessment Platform (which the domain scores had been modelled for to date.)</li>
	<li><code>Time Table Change Reason List Type</code> and <code>Time Table Change Reason Type</code>,
	requested by Timetabling Solutions, to indicate the kinds
	of change to timetabling being published through the <code>ScheduledActivity</code> object.</li>
	<li>Aggressive refactoring of XML Element + Attribute combinations into distinct types, in order to make 
	conversion to PESC JSON and back more straightforward:
	results in new common types <code>Activity Evaluation Type</code> (from <code>Activity</code>), 
	<code>Calculation Rule Type</code> (from <code>AggregateStaticticInfo</code>), <code>Learning Resource Location Type</code>
	(from <code>Learning Resource</code>), <code>PictureSourceType</code> (from <code>PersonPicture</code>),
	<code>Duration Type</code> (from common type <code>Activity Time Type</code>),
	<code>Identity Assertion Type</code> (from common type <code>Identity Assertions Type</code>), 
	<code>TypedIdRefType</code> (for all <code>RefIdType</code> + <code>@SIF_RefObject</code> combinations).</li>
 </ul>
	
	<h4>New CodeSets</h4>
	<ul>	
	<li>Added <code>Time Table Change Type</code>, requested by Timetabling Solutions, to indicate the kinds
	of change to timetabling being published through the <code>ScheduledActivity</code> object.</li>
	</ul>

	<h4>Additions to CodeSets</h4>
	<ul>	
	<li>Added <code>Federal Electorates</code>&#x2014;<code>219</code>, <code>Hawke</code>.</li>
	</ul>

	<h4>Removals/Deprecations from CodeSets</h4>
	<ul>	
	<li>Deprecated <code>Relationship to Student</code>&#x2014;<code>03</code>, <code>Adoptive parent</code>, 
	in favour of <code>Parent</code>, requested by DET VIC.</li>
	<li>Removed <code>Federal Electorates</code>&#x2014;<code>514</code>, <code>Stirling</code>, 
	abolished at the 2022 federal election.</li>
	</ul>


	<h4>Other Changes</h4>
	<ul><li>Significant refactoring and debugging of OpenAPI version of standard, with fully validated
	OpenAPI 3.0.4 version, restricted to PESC JSON output, and OpenAPI 3.1.0 version, intended for
	online publishing.</li>
	<li>Change to <code>Relationship to Student</code>&#x2014;<code>00</code>, <code>Spouse</code>, 
	updated to <code>Spouse/Partner</code> with annotation that it is expected to be rare,
	requested by DET VIC.</li>
	<li><code>Demographics/Sex</code> is redefined to mean biological sex; the use of the element
	to date	to convey gender identity will henceforth be taken over by <code>Demographics/Gender</code>, 
	in order to align naming to current practice.</li>
	<li>Modelled <code>Monetary Amount Type</code> explicitly as an extension (i.e. an addition of an XML
	attribute to a pre-existing type), for better translation to PESC JSON.</li>
	<li>Documentation added to <code>TimeTable</code> and <code>ScheduledActivity</code> objects, following
	proposal from Timetabling Solutions, on how to use <code>ScheduledActivity</code> to publish timetabling
	changes, including indicating the start date of the timetabling cycle.</li>
 	</ul>
   	
	<h4>Corrections</h4>
	<ul>
		<li></li>

   </ul>
   
</Section>
