<Appendix name="Notes on Related Technologies">

		<Intro>
			<p>
				This partially normative appendix highlights technologies
				leveraged within SIF or related to SIF, either in their entirety or as a subset.  It points out specifics casual readers
				of referenced documents on these technologies must not ignore when implementing SIF Zone Integration Servers and Agents.
			</p>
		</Intro>
		
		<Section name="SIF and HTTP(S)">
			<p>
				SIF uses a small subset of HTTP 1.1 (SIF HTTP), as defined in <a href="Architecture.html#InfrastructureTransportLayer">
					Infrastructure
					Transport Layer
				</a>, to promote interoperability.  This section also defines a secure transport for SIF HTTP, SIF HTTPS, the required
				and default transport layer for use in SIF.
			</p>
		</Section>
		<Section name="SIF and URLs">
			<p>
				Zone Integration Servers and Push-mode Agents, when using SIF HTTPS or SIF HTTP, are addressable by an <code>http</code> or <code>https</code>
				Uniform Resource Locator (URL).  As far as HTTP is concerned, these are simply formatted strings; no assumptions should be made about their format
				(e.g. that all ZIS URLs consist of a host, port and Zone Id, or that all agent URLs consist of a host, port and Agent Id )
				beyond the <code>http</code> and <code>https</code> schemes and the consituent parts from the generic URI (Uniform Resource Identifier) syntax
				<a href="References.html#RFC2396">[RFC 2396]</a>.
			</p>
			<p>
				<code>http://</code><i>host</i>[<code>:</code><i>port</i>][<i>abs_path</i>[<code>?</code><i>query</i>]]<br/>
				<code>http://</code><i>host</i>[<code>:</code><i>port</i>][<i>abs_path</i>[<code>?</code><i>query</i>]]
			</p>
			<p>Just because one Zone Integration Server seems to follow a certain convention with regard to its URLs, e.g.:</p>
			<p>
				<code>http://www.YourZIS.com/YourZone</code>
			</p>
			<p>does not imply another Zone Integration Server will not have a completely different format for a URL, for instance:</p>
			<p>
				<code>http://www.ZISesAreUs.com:8080/applications/ZIS;version=2.3.1?zone=ZoneA&amp;cust=2A9823B2</code>
			</p>
			<p>or that a vendor's product might not change its URL conventions.</p>
			<p>
				The same applies to URLs that address Push-mode Agents; conventions for URLs, within the general formatting that applies to
				URLs, can and do vary widely.
			</p>
			<p>
				Zone Integration Servers and Agents <span class="rfc2119">MUST</span> treat SIF HTTPS and SIF HTTP URLs as whole strings, whose
				only format rules stem from associated standards.  This promotes interoperability as Zone administrators deploy Zone Integration
				Servers and Agents with different Zone configurations and products from different vendors.
			</p>
		</Section>
		<Section name="SIF and XML">
			<p>
				With its use in both Infrastructure and the SIF Data Model, SIF is greatly dependent on the structure
				and syntax of XML 1.0 <a href="References.html#XML">[XML]</a>.
				SIF excludes the use of the <code>doctypedecl</code> syntax from the optional <code>prolog</code> with which every XML document may begin.
				This implies that Zone Integration Servers and Agents <span class="rfc2119">MUST NOT</span> reference an external DTD or internal DTD
				subset using the <code>doctypedecl</code> production (e.g. <code>&lt;!DOCTYPE SIF_Message ... !&gt;</code>).
			</p>
			<p>
				This should not be construed to imply that the rest of the XML <code>prolog</code> may not preface a SIF message, even though it
				never occurs in examples within this specification, being superfluous within SIF.  As SIF mandates the use of XML 1.0, the
				character encoding of <code>UTF-8</code> (contained in the HTTP <code>Content-Type</code> header), and all SIF messages are <code>standalone</code> due to the exclusion of <code>doctypedecl</code>
				above, the values that can be communicated in the XML <code>prolog</code> are fixed within SIF.  This implies that if a Zone Integration Server or
				Agent includes an XML <code>prolog</code> before a SIF message, it <span class="rfc2119">MUST</span> take one of the following or equivalent forms
				(equivalent including case-insensitive character encoding names, XML's choice with regard to single or double quotes and optional spacing):
			</p>
			<p>
				<code>&lt;?xml version="1.0"?&gt;</code>
				<br/>
				<code>&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?&gt;</code>
				<br/>
				<code>&lt;?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?&gt;</code>
				<br/>
				<code>&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?&gt;</code>
				<br/>
			</p>
		</Section>
		<Section name="SIF and Unicode">
			<p>
				The character set supported in XML 1.0 is Unicode/ISO 10646, a character set designed to be universal in nature with regard to its
				support for previously used character sets in the computer industry, ability to represent most human languages, numbers,
				commonly used symbols, etc.  Thus the character set supported in SIF is Unicode/ISO 10646.
				If a Zone Integration Server or SIF-enabled application does not support Unicode/ISO 10646 internally, it <span class="rfc2119">MUST</span>
				map Unicode/ISO 10646 to its local character set upon receipt of a SIF message and <span class="rfc2119">MUST</span> map its
				local character set to Unicode/ISO 10646 when sending or responding to a SIF message.  To promote interoperability and prevent loss of data in
				these conversions, it is <span class="rfc2119">RECOMMENDED</span> that all Zone
				Integration Servers and SIF-enabled applications support Unicode/ISO 10646.
			</p>
			<p>
				SIF HTTP further requires that the Unicode/ISO 10646 character set be encoded using the UTF-8 character encoding; Zone Integration
				Servers and Agents <span class="rfc2119">MUST</span> encode SIF XML messages using UTF-8.  To further promote interoperability, when the SIF
				Infrastructure or Data Model specifies that an octet/byte-based transformation of a text/string value be stored in a given element or attribute
				(e.g. Base64 encoding, hash value, encrypted form), Zone Integration Servers and Agents <span class="rfc2119">MUST</span> convert
				the local character set of the value to Unicode/ISO 10646 if necessary, encode the resulting value using UTF-8, then apply the specified
				transformation.
			</p>
		</Section>
		<Section name="SIF and XPath">
			<p>
				SIF uses a small subset of XPath 1.0 <a href="References.html">[XPATH]</a> in its own path syntax for referencing elements/attributes.
				This is defined in <a href="Infrastructure.html#SIF_ElementSyntax">SIF_Element Syntax</a>.  This document may often use the same notation
				in referring to nested elements and/or attributes (e.g. <code>Name/FirstName</code>, <code>Name/@Type</code>), though it may include an
				object as the root element whereas the SIF_Element syntax does not (e.g. <code>StudentPersonal/Name/FirstName</code>,
				<code>StudentPersonal/@RefId</code>).
			</p>
		</Section>
		<Section name="SIF and XML Schema">
			<p>
				The SIF Association hosts and provides XML Schemas <a href="References.html#SCHEMA">[SCHEMA]</a> for validating SIF messages, should Zone Integration Servers
				or Agents choose to perform message validation.  These schemas leverage basic data types and structures as defined in that document.  When
				these types and structures are referenced in this document they are prefixed with <code>xs:</code>.
			</p>
			<p>
				Note that due to the ability of Zone Integration Servers and Agents to omit elements from data objects in the SIF Request/Response and
				SIF Event models,
				all elements defined as mandatory for SIF data objects in <a href="Infrastructure.html#DataObjects">Infrastructure</a> or
				<a href="DataModel.html#DataObjects">Data Model</a> and referenced common elements
				are defined as optional in the schema for validating any SIF_Message.  The SIF Association hosts and provides alternate schemas that allow for validation of these
				data objects where mandatory elements cannot be omitted (e.g. in a <code>Add</code> event or in a <code>SIF_Response</code>
				where the <code>SIF_Request</code> did not specify a specific subset of elements to be returned from matching objects).
			</p>
			<p>Notes on specific XML Schema types follow:</p>
			<Section name="xs:boolean">
				<p>
					Agents and Zone Integration servers <span class="rfc2119">SHOULD</span> send values of <code>true</code> or <code>false</code>, but
					must understand equivalent <code>1</code> and <code>0</code> values.
				</p>
			</Section>
			<Section name="xs:time">
				<p>
					Agents and Zone Integration Servers <span class="rfc2119">MUST</span> specify a time zone offset from UTC or indicate that the time is UTC unless
					the time zone is apparent locally from other elements/attributes per supplied documentation.
				</p>
			</Section>
				<Section name="xs:date">
					<p>
						Agents and Zone Integration Servers <span class="rfc2119">MAY</span> specify a time zone offset or indicate UTC for dates, but in most cases
						do not need to do so unless zone activity spans great international distances.
					</p>
				</Section>
				<Section name="xs:dateTime">
					<p>
						Agents and Zone Integration Servers <span class="rfc2119">MUST</span> specify a time zone offset from UTC or indicate that the time is UTC unless
						the time zone is apparent locally from other elements/attributes per supplied documentation.
					</p>
					<p>Though use of a combined <code>xs:dateTime</code> may seem a natural fit for specifying a point in time, 
					some SIF Association working groups and task forces prefer to separate <code>xs:dateTime</code> into element/attribute pairs of <code>xs:date</code> and 
						<code>xs:time</code> per their object design/usage goals and/or for simplified quering.  Applications wishing to query the date or time
						portion of <code>xs:dateTime</code>	values may use comparison and boolean operators to do so.
				</p>
				</Section>
			</Section>
		<Section name="SIF and XML Namespaces">
			<p>
				Namespaces allow XML elements and attributes to be organized into units that allow for the separation of a set of names from others,
				effectively allowing the integration of XML defined from various sources to be included in the same XML document without risk of name/definition
				collisions.  SIF has since its initial release used the default namespace attribute <code>xmlns</code>&#160;<a href="References.html#XMLNS">[XMLNS]</a> in
				the <code>SIF_Message</code> element.  To a namespace-aware parser, the effective names of the elements in:
			</p>
			<xhtml:Example xmlns=""  name="SIF_Message Namespace" validate="false">
				<SIF_Message xmlns="http://www.sifinfo.org/infrastructure/1.x" Version="1.5r1">
					<SIF_Event>...</SIF_Event>
				</SIF_Message>
			</xhtml:Example>
			<p>are conceptually:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>
					<code>http://www.sifinfo.org/infrastructure/1.x:SIF_Message</code>
				</li>
				<li>
					<code>http://www.sifinfo.org/infrastructure/1.x:SIF_Event</code>
				</li>
			</ul>
			<p>with the local names:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>
					<code>SIF_Message</code>
				</li>
				<li>
					<code>SIF_Event</code>
				</li>
			</ul>
			<p>
				To a namespace-aware parser, the effective names of these same elements in the SIF <code>2.x</code> namespace:
			</p>
			<xhtml:Example xmlns="" name="SIF_Message Namespace" validate="false">
				<SIF_Message xmlns="http://www.sifinfo.org/infrastructure/2.x" Version="2.3">
					<SIF_Event>...</SIF_Event>
				</SIF_Message>
			</xhtml:Example>
			<p>are conceptually:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>
					<code>http://www.sifinfo.org/infrastructure/2.x:SIF_Message</code>
				</li>
				<li>
					<code>http://www.sifinfo.org/infrastructure/2.x:SIF_Event</code>
				</li>
			</ul>
			<p>with the local names:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>
					<code>SIF_Message</code>
				</li>
				<li>
					<code>SIF_Event</code>
				</li>
			</ul>
			<p>
				A namespace-unaware parser simply interprets elements by their local names, and SIF 1.x and SIF 2.x elements are considered equivalent.
				If the local name is prefixed, a namespace-unaware
				parser considers the prefix and colon part of the name.  To a namespace-unaware parser, <code>xml:lang</code> is named just that.
				To a namespace-aware parser, this is effectively <code>http://www.w3.org/XML/1998/namespace:lang</code> (the <code>xml</code> prefix
				is reserved in XML 1.0 and is always bound to this namespace in <a href="References.html#XMLNS">[XMLNS]</a>) with a local name of
				<code>lang</code>.
			</p>
			<p>
				Given the timing of the first release of SIF and the release of <a href="References.html#XMLNS">Namespaces in XML [XMLNS]</a>
				it was never mandated in SIF that Zone Integration Servers and Agents be namespace-aware.  Given the number of Zone Integration Servers
				and Agents that may at this point be namespace-unaware, it is not yet mandated that these components be namespace-aware,
				but this requirement may arise in a future major release of this specification.  To allow for namespace-unaware parsers to
				reliably process SIF-defined XML by local names only, SIF messages <span class="rfc2119">MUST</span> define the namespace
				for the corresponding SIF version as the default namespace of <code>SIF_Message</code> as documented in <a href="Infrastructure.html#SIF_Message">
					<code>SIF_Message</code>
				</a>.
			</p>
			<p>
				Furthermore, given the gradual proliferation of XML defined in other namespaces appearing in SIF XML, the following prefix-to-namespace
				mappings <span class="rfc2119">MUST</span> be used should elements from these namespaces occur in SIF messages,
				to allow namespace-unaware parsers to reliably interpret names in these namespaces by local name:
			</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr>
						<th>Prefix</th>
						<th>Namespace</th>
						<th>Declaration</th>
					</tr>
				</thead>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<code>xml</code>
					</td>
					<td>
						<code>http://www.w3.org/XML/1998/namespace</code>
					</td>
					<td>This is bound and fixed by default without declaration.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<code>xsi</code>
					</td>
					<td>
						<code>http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance</code>
					</td>
					<td>
						<code>xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"</code>
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<code>xs</code>
					</td>
					<td>
						<code>http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema</code>
					</td>
					<td>
						<code>xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"</code>
					</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
			<p>
				It is <span class="rfc2119">RECOMMENDED</span> that other namespaces occuring in SIF messages (e.g. XML from outside SIF
				included in assessments, exchange of student records, etc.) have fixed prefix mappings, but it is not required.  Affected elements
				<span class="rfc2119">MAY</span> locally change the default namespace as desired, given that the default namespace for the <code>
					SIF_Message
				</code> as a whole remains the namespace for the corresponding SIF version.
			</p>
			<p>
				When a fixed
				prefix is not defined for a given namespace, a namespace-unaware agent will be unable to reliably process these elements by
				name when prefixes vary, and must become namespace-aware to do so.  XML not defined by SIF that in turn contains
				SIF-defined XML <span class="rfc2119">MAY</span> reference SIF XML by its own prefix mapping rather than specifying
				the namespace of the corresponding SIF version as the default namespace using <code>xmlns</code>.
			</p>
			<p>
				It is <span class="rfc2119">RECOMMENDED</span> that as Zone Integration Servers and Agents are updated in their release schedules,
				they use namespace-aware parsers or parser options if they are not doing so already.
			</p>
		</Section>
		<Section name="SIF and UUIDs/GUIDs">
			<p>
				SIF leverages Universally Unique Identifiers (UUIDs), or Globally Unique Identifiers (GUIDs), as message and object identifiers, or primary keys,
				and occasionally for element identifiers internal to objects, per <a href="References.html#RFC4122">[RFC 4122]</a>.
				Note that SIF defines its own textual representation for GUIDs, uppercase and un-hyphenated (e.g. <code>F81D4FAE7DEC11D0A76500A0C91E6BF6</code> vs.
				<code>f81d4fae-7dec-11d0-a765-00a0c91e6bf6</code>).  It should also be noted with SIF being a distributed system, to avoid the possibility
				of GUID collisions, especially in the SIF data model, systems generating GUIDs <span class="rfc2119">SHOULD</span> use version 1 GUIDs which are
				unique in space as well as time when an IEEE 802 MAC address is available.  Systems <span class="rfc2119">MAY</span> use version 4 GUIDs which use
				a (pseudo-)random number-based algorithm if an IEEE 802 MAC address is unavailable or if the inclusion of that address in a GUID poses a compromising
				security risk.
			</p>
		</Section>
		<Section name="SIF and Web Services">
			<p>
				SIF is a web service, "a software system designed to support interoperable machine-to-machine interaction over a network <a href="References.html#WSARCH">[WSARCH]</a>."
				It is not a Web Service, as it lacks "an interface described in a machine-processable format
				(specifically WSDL) <a href="References.html#WSARCH">[WSARCH]</a>."  To meet this requirement and produce the Web Services Definition
				Language (WSDL) definition for
				SIF is a trivial exercise, creating a WSDL HTTP POST binding for the <code>SIF_Message</code>-in/<code>SIF_Message</code>-out exchange that describes
				the SIF HTTP(S) transport layer between Agents and ZIS, and between ZIS and Push-mode Agents.  But the binding would be just that,
				a simple <code>SIF_Message</code>-in/<code>SIF_Message</code>-out exchange
				that doesn't capture the richness of the SIF infrastructure or necessarily provide the interoperability resulting from the precise
				definition of SIF HTTP(S).  To do so and to meet the final requirement of a Web Service per <a href="References.html#WSARCH">[WSARCH]</a>,
				the use of SOAP messages, would require redefinition of much of SIF using SOAP messages.  The SIF Association's Web Services Task Force has determined that this exercise has little
				value currently, given SIF's precisely defined transport layer and installed base.  The task force has left it as a future task how to best leverage
				Web Services in the future of SIF's infrastructure, if at all.  In the meantime, the task force has, however, decided to provide a Web Services interface that provides external systems
				access to the rich amount of data available in SIF Zones via its own specification <a href="References.html#SIFReportingWS">[SIF Reporting WS]</a>.  Future opportunities to provide additional services
				may be identified.
			</p>
		</Section>
	</Appendix>